Courage. Family. Honor.
Mulan is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Tony Bancroft.
To save her father from certain death in the army, a young woman secretly enlists in
his place and becomes one of China's greatest heroines in the process.
Mulan (voice), played by Ming-Na Wen.
Mushu (voice), played by Eddie Murphy.
Shang (voice), played by BD Wong.
Shan-Yu (voice), played by Miguel Ferrer.
Yao (voice), played by Harvey Fierstein.
Fa Li (voice), played by Freda Foh Shen.
Mulan is a 1998 American animated musical coming-of-age action-adventure film based on the
Chinese legend of Hua Mulan, and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
The film was directed by Barry Cook and Tony Bancroft and produced by Pam Coats, from a screenplay by Rita Hsiao, Chris Sanders,
Philip LaZebnik, and the writing team of Raymond Singer and Eugenia Bostwick-Singer, and a story by Robert D.
Ming-Na Wen, Eddie Murphy, Miguel Ferrer, and BD Wong star in the English version as Mulan, Mushu, Shan Yu, and Captain Li
Shang, respectively, while Jackie Chan provided the voice of Li Shang for the Chinese dubs of the film.
The film's plot takes place in China during an unspecified Imperial dynasty, where Fa Mulan, daughter of aged warrior Fa
Zhou, impersonates a man to take her father's place during a general conscription to counter a Hun invasion.
Mulan was the first of three features produced primarily at the Disney animation studio at
Disney–MGM Studios (now Disney's Hollywood Studios) in Bay Lake, Florida.
Development for the film began in 1994, when a number of artistic supervisors
were sent to China to receive artistic and cultural inspiration.
Mulan premiered at the Hollywood Bowl in Los Angeles on June 5,
1998, and was released in the United States on June 19.
The film received positive reviews from critics and the public, who praised the animation,
plot, characters (particularly the title character), and musical score.
It was a commercial success, grossing over $304 million
worldwide against a production budget of $90 million.
It earned a Golden Globe and Academy Award nomination for its music and
won several Annie Awards, including Best Animated Feature.
It was then followed by a direct-to-video sequel, Mulan II in 2004.
A live-action remake directed by Niki Caro was released on September 4, 2020.
The film explores themes of princess, daughter, china, homeland, villain.